<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Overview reports"
       id="cloud-overview-reports">

    <p>Information from project reports is aggregated and displayed in several fields.</p>

        <img src="qc-overview-reports.png" dark-src="qc-overview-reports_dark.png" alt="Qodana Cloud report overview" width="706" border-effect="line" title="Qodana Cloud report sample"/>

        <p>This sample project contains the following fields:</p>

    <list>
        <li>Project name</li>
        <li>Branch name</li>
        <li>Commit description</li>
        <li>Date and time of the latest Qodana inspection</li>
        <li>Number of problems detected and severity expressed as a circle. The circle color reflects the severity of
            the major part of detected problems. You can click this element to open the report</li>
        <li>The upper-right corner contains the dropdown list to let you rename the project, copy its token, or delete
            it from Qodana Cloud</li>
    </list>

    <p>This table shows how Qodana Cloud interprets and displays several reports depending on their metadata.</p>

    <table>
        <tr>
            <td>Branch name</td>
            <td>Commit time</td>
            <td>Commit hash</td>
            <td>Displays</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>The same</td>
            <td>The same</td>
            <td>N/A</td>
            <td>The latest report and overwrites the previous reports</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>The same</td>
            <td>Different</td>
            <td>N/A</td>
            <td>Separate reports</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
            <td>N/A</td>
            <td>N/A</td>
            <td>The same</td>
            <td>Single report</td>
        </tr>
    </table>

    <p>To see all reports related to the project, click the project name. This will open the
        <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/qodana/ui-overview.html">Qodana report page</a>. </p>

    <img src="qc-report-overview.png" dark-src="qc-report-overview_dark.png" alt="Report overview" width="706" border-effect="line"/>

    <p>The upper part of this page contains:</p>

    <p>1. Branch selector. Using it, you can overview reports for each branch in your project.</p>
    <p>2. Commit name and date.</p>
    <p>3. Timeline describing the date of inspection and number of problems detected.</p>
    <p>4. Selector for overviewing either the absolute number of detected problems, or the number of problems
    relatively to a <a href="qodana-baseline.xml">baseline</a> set for this project.</p>

</topic>
