<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Qodana Cloud use-cases"
       id="cloud-use-cases">

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-1" title="Get deeper insights into your project trends" level="4">

        <p>Using Qodana Cloud, you can aggregate Qodana reports from various projects, explore development trends, and
            analyze team and project performance.</p>

        <p>To organize your work, Qodana Cloud provides a hierarchy consisting of organizations, teams, and projects.
            These entities let you assign several projects to a single team. Also, you can achieve transparency using
            real-time widgets.</p>

        <p>Each project stores history of inspection results and compares results between commits. You can examine the
            absolute number of problems detected, or compare the number of problems against a baseline taken during a
            specific Qodana run.</p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-2" title="Open problems detected by Qodana in your favorite IDE" level="4">

        <p>If you are already a Qodana user, you might know that you can open issues spotted by Qodana right in your IDE.
            This feature is available in Qodana Cloud meaning that you can fix server-side errors in the editor like
            you work with other suggestions given by the IDE.</p>

        <p>Using Qodana, you can run resource-intensive checks outside your development environment without affecting
            performance of your IDE. In fact, we created Qodana to ensure that you no longer have to choose between code
            quality and IDE performance.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-3" title="Plan your work better" level="4">

        <p>In Qodana Cloud, you can build reports to evaluate all pieces of code that require modification, and select
            issues to add to baseline. This way, the whole team can see the same list of issues and monitor progress
            using the interactive Qodana dashboard.</p>
    </chapter>
</topic>
