<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Qodana Cloud use-cases"
       id="cloud-use-cases">

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-1" title="You are responsible for product quality" level="4">

    <p>In case you primary job is management rather than coding, you should know the answer to the "How things are going?"
        question at any time. You can track the development process using reports from version control systems, bug
        trackers, and during meetings. Still, monitoring of software quality is missing, and you can only refer to
        conclusions from your team leaders or architects. Looking at the code cannot help you in this case. Also,
        collecting information about quality code can be a tedious task. You can use %product% to automate the quality
        assessment process, and %product_cloud% will let you see the overall picture.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-2" title="You work for an outsourcing company that resells IT services" level="4">
    <p>Your company may deal with lots of various projects from different fields, which makes it difficult to be
        expert in all of them. Oftentimes, software products are developed on the customers' side, but quality
        monitoring is still part of your work. Using %product_cloud% as an aggregator of %product% reports will
        definitely help you in this case. </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-3" title="Your company relies on open source" level="4">
    <p> Today's software products often resort to open source libraries to
        perform specific tasks. This approach saves companies time and money. Unfortunately, nobody could assure you
        that their code is free of bugs, and their licenses will meet your needs. Besides that, you cannot control the
        process of open source development. Using %product% on GitHub, you can monitor quality of open source software
        used in your project, and the License Audit linter will inspect all licenses. But if your project uses tens or
        hundreds of free libraries, this becomes a challenging task. Using %product_cloud% allows you to aggregate tons
        of reports under a single roof.</p>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="cloud-use-case-4" title="Your company purchases software from third-party vendors" level="4">
    <p>In case your company buys software from the outside, you
        still need to make sure that its quality meets your needs. Using %product% will give you detailed reports
        generated by tried-and-tested software from JetBrains, and %product_cloud% will aggregate reports from all
        %product% instances.</p>
    </chapter>
</topic>
