<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Frequently asked questions"
       id="faq.xml">

<p>Here is the collection of questions that will help you better understand basic %product% concepts.</p>

<chapter title="General questions" id="faq-supported-technologies">

    <chapter id="faq-how-can-i-run" title="How can I run %product%?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

    <p>You can run %product% in your <a href="ci.md">CI pipelines</a>. You can inspect your code locally using either the
    <a href="qodana-ide-plugin.md">JetBrains IDEs</a> or available <a href="docker-images.md">Docker images</a>.</p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-integrate-cicd" title="How can I build Qodana into <CI/CD name> pipelines?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

    <p>Any %product% linter is a Linux Docker image, so any CI/CD that supports Docker should be able to run it.
    We are working on <a href="ci.md">extending our documentation</a> to provide the best examples on how to integrate it with
    different CI/CD platforms. If you experience any difficulties, feel free to contact our support at
    <code>qodana-support@jetbrains.com</code>.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-integrate-custom-checks" title="Does Qodana support custom checks?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>At the moment, you can add your <a href="extending-qodana-structural-search.xml">structural search inspections</a> to
    the inspection profile or use <a href="extending-qodana-plugins.xml">plugins</a> that will extend inspection
    capabilities of %product%.</p>
    <p>Alternatively, you can develop <a href="https://plugins.jetbrains.com/docs/intellij/github-template.html">your own plugin</a> and
    use its inspections with %product%.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-self-hosted-on-premises" title="Is there an option for a self-hosted or on-premises version of Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can run %product% under the Community license, which will not require from you to create a Qodana Cloud account.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-support-other-techs" title="Are there any plans to support other technologies?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>The list of technologies already supported by %product% is available on the <a href="linters.md"/> page.</p>

        <p>All technologies supported by JetBrains IDEs are going to be eventually covered by %product%. You can create an issue on
            our tracker or vote for an existing one to let us know what technology we should focus on, for example:</p>

        <list>
            <li><a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/QD-1031">Scala</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/QD-2226">Dart</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/QD-2153">C/C++</a></li>
            <li><a href="https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/issue/QD-2122">Code coverage</a></li>
        </list>

    </chapter>

</chapter>


<chapter title="Deployment and configuration" id="faq-deployment-and-configuration">

    <chapter id="faq-customization-required" title="Can I use Qodana right away, or is customization required?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can use various ways to run %product% as described on the <a href="Quick-start.xml"/> page. All of them require the
    minimum number of preparation steps.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-linter-description" title="What does each %product% linter represent?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>A linter is a %product% component representing a specific technology. For example, the
    <a href="qodana-jvm.md"/> linter lets you inspect the codebase containing the Java, Kotlin, and Groovy code, while
    using the <a href="qodana-js.md"/> linter you can check the JavaScript and TypeScript code. On the <a href="linters.md"/>
    page, you can find the list of all available linters and the links to the detailed description of each linter.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-multiple-linters" title="Can I use multiple linters in one project?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can use multiple linters as described in the <a href="monorepo-project.md"/> section.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-check-customization" title="How can I customize the checks performed by Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can configure your inspection profile as described on the <a href="custom-profiles.md"/> page.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-ssh-key-setup" title="Why is there a need to set up SSH keys in my repository?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>The SSH key lets %product% identify the repository of the inspected project and calculate the number of contributors,
    which is a requirement for all types of <a href="pricing.md">licenses</a>.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-qodana-cloud-use" title="Do I really need Qodana Cloud if I want to use Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>Using Qodana Cloud, you can get access to all
    <a href="pricing.md" anchor="Features+and+third-party+software+support">features</a> provided by %product%
        <a href="linters.md">linters</a>. You can also open %product% reports using your <a href="qodana-ide-plugin.md">IDE</a>,
        and you need Qodana Cloud for these purposes.</p>
    </chapter>

</chapter>

<chapter title="Inspection profiles" id="faq-inspection-profiles">

    <chapter id="faq-profile-explained" title="What is a profile?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>A %product% profile is a set of pre-configured inspections including their state, configuration options, and
    the path they are applied to. %product% inspection profiles are the same as IntelliJ IDEA inspection profiles and they
    can be <a href="custom-xml-profiles.md">reused</a>.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-what-profiles-offered" title="What inspection profiles does Qodana offer?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can find the list of the default %product% inspection profiles on the <a href="inspection-profiles.md" anchor="Default+profiles"/> page.
    On that page, you can also study how to set up the default profiles.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-how-select-profile" title="How can I select the best profile for my project?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>You can use the <a href="inspection-profiles.md" anchor="Default+profiles"><code>qodana.recommended</code></a> profile
    because it already provides the most usable inspections invoked by the default JetBrains IDEs profiles, so no additional configuration
    is required.</p>
    <p>Alternatively, you can <a href="custom-profiles.md">create</a> your own profile that will best fit your goals.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-sarif-import" title="Can I import SARIF of another analysis tool to Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>No, currently there is no opportunity to show the results of external analysis tools in %product% UI, though we are working on it.</p>
    </chapter>

</chapter>

<chapter title="Licensing" id="faq-licensing">

    <chunk id="faq-licensing-for-pricing">
    <chapter id="faq-licensing-minimum-contributors" title="I work solo on my project, can I still use Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>Yes, but the minimum billing is set for 3 (three) contributors.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-count-contributors" title="Is there a way to determine the number of contributors in my repositories prior to initiating Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>Yes, you can use this command to check the number of contributors:</p>
        <code style="block" lang="shell" prompt="$">
            git log --format='%aN' | sort -u | wc -l
        </code>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-start-using-qodana" title="What do I need to start using Qodana?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <list>
            <li><p>You can navigate to the <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/qodana/buy/">Subscription Options and Pricing</a> page on
                the JetBrains website and select the subscription option you would like to use.</p>
                <p>If you choose the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus trial license, you will be redirected to the
                    <a href="cloud-onboarding.md">onboarding</a> page of Qodana Cloud. This is also applicable for the Community license.</p>
                <p>If you plan to purchase either the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus license, you’ll be redirected to the JetBrains account
                    page for payment details. After the payment, you will be redirected to the <a href="cloud-onboarding.md">onboarding</a> page of
                    Qodana Cloud.</p>
            </li>
            <li>During the onboarding stage on the Qodana Cloud website, you’ll generate a public key that will be
                identified by %product%, as well as a project token for uploading %product% reports to your first project.
                Although the Community license does not require a Qodana Cloud account, it will be more convenient to use Qodana Cloud
                in this case too.</li>
        </list>
        <note>The Community license provides restricted functionalities compared to the Ultimate and Ultimate Plus licenses. See
            <a href="pricing.md" anchor="license-comparison-matrix">the comparison matrix</a> for more details.</note>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-try-before-buy" title="Can I try Qodana before buying a license?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>Yes, you can choose either the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus trial license and start using Qodana for a 60-day trial period.
            After 60 days, you’ll need to buy either the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus license to continue using Qodana in your projects.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-linters-and-cloud" title="What are %product% linters and Qodana Cloud designed for?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>Both %product% linters and Qodana Cloud are essential parts of the product named %product%. You can inspect your codebase
            using %product% linters, and you can use Qodana Cloud for managing your projects and licenses, as well as collecting
            %product% reports in a single place. For more details, see the <a href="cloud-use-cases.xml"/> page of the Qodana Cloud
            documentation.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-using-without-cloud" title="Can I use %product% linters without creating a Qodana Cloud account?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>If you plan to use the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus licenses, you have to create an account at Qodana Cloud and accomplish
            the <a href="cloud-onboarding.md">onboarding</a> stage. For more details, see the
            <a anchor="faq-licensing-start-using-qodana">question</a> in this section.</p>
        <p>You can run Community linters of %product% without using Qodana Cloud, but you will not be able to make use
            of Qodana Cloud <a href="cloud-use-cases.xml">features</a>.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-minimum-cloud-steps" title="What minimum steps do I need to perform in Qodana Cloud?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>All the required steps are described in the <a href="cloud-quickstart.md"/> section of the Qodana Cloud documentation.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-eap-trial" title="What are the EAP and trial licenses?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>An EAP license is a license that gives you full access to Qodana until July 31, 2023. On August 1, 2023, all EAP
        licenses will expire, which means users will have to switch to a trial license.</p>

        <p>A trial license is a time-limited version of either the Ultimate or the Ultimate Plus license. Each trial license
        duration is limited to 60 days, after which this type of license is no longer valid and cannot be used further. To
            continue using %product%, you’ll have to buy a full version of your license.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-trial-notification" title="Will I be notified when the license trial period comes to an end?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>Yes, you’ll be notified when the trial period expires.</p>
        <p>After its expiry, you’ll need to buy either the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus license. Expired trial licenses cannot be extended.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-payment-details" title="Do I need to provide payment details for a trial license?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>No, you don’t have to provide any payment details until you decide to buy a license for either the Ultimate or Ultimate
            Plus version of Qodana, which you can do after the trial period ends.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-switching-licenses" title="Can I switch between licenses?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>Yes, you can switch one time between trial versions of the Ultimate and Ultimate Plus licenses using your
            JetBrains Account.</p>

        <p>You can also switch one time from the trial version of the Ultimate and Ultimate Plus licenses to the Community license.
            Once you convert your trial license to the Community license, the process is irreversible. Ensure you are making an
            informed decision. Remember that the Community license does not support all the
            <a href="pricing.md" anchor="Features+and+third-party+software+support">features</a> available in the
            Ultimate or Ultimate Plus subscriptions. If you wish to revert back to the Ultimate or Ultimate Plus
            subscription after conversion, you will need to initiate a paid subscription.</p>

        <p>After the trial period has ended, this one-time limitation is shifted, and you can switch between subscription
            plans the unlimited number of times. In this case, however, all purchased subscriptions are not refunded.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-license-costs" title="What are the license costs comprised of?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p> The total license cost is based on the number of active contributors. An active contributor is a person who commits
            to any number of Qodana Cloud projects during the latest 90 days, within the same organization, and under a single
            license. During the <a href="cloud-onboarding.md">onboarding</a> stage and while creating a new
            <a href="cloud-projects.xml">project</a>, Qodana Cloud requests your repository URL to calculate
            contributors. The minimal number of contributors used for licensing is 3 (three).</p>

        <p>The number of actual contributors is calculated based on the subscription plan. For example, using the monthly
            subscription, on the 1st day of the month you bought a license for 10 (ten) contributors. Within that same
            month, Qodana found that your project had 20 (twenty) active contributors. In this case, for the upcoming
            month the license costs would be recalculated for 20 (twenty) contributors. At the end of the second month,
            the license costs would be recalculated again based on the actual number of active contributors found
            within that month.</p>

        <p>For more details, see the <menupath>Fees and Payments</menupath> section of the
            <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/legal/docs/agreements/qodana/license/">%product% Terms of Service</a>.</p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-minimum-contributors" title="What is the minimum number of contributors I can buy the license for?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>You can buy a %product% license for 3 (three) or more contributors.</p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-subscription-billing" title="What do I need to know about subscription billing?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>Here is the billing description taken from the
            <a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/legal/docs/agreements/qodana/license/">%product% Terms of Service</a>:
        </p>

        <p><menupath>Monthly Subscriptions</menupath> - At the beginning of each Subscription Period, You will specify the expected number of
            Active Contributors (3 or more). At the end of the Subscription Period, You will be charged Subscription fees according
            to Your Subscription Plan based on the number of Active Contributors that You determined. Qodana checks the actual
            number of Active Contributors at the end of every Subscription Period. If that number is higher than the number of
            Active Contributors that You specified for that Subscription Period, You will not be charged for overuse. However, the
            number of Active Contributors You specify for the next Subscription Period cannot be lower than the actual number from
            the preceding Subscription Period.</p>
        <p><menupath>Annual Subscriptions</menupath> - Fees for annual Subscriptions are charged as a combination of upfront payment for a number
            of Active Contributors selected by You and additional charges for Active Contributors exceeding the prepaid number
            during the Subscription Period (overuse):</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <li><menupath>Prepayment</menupath> – At the beginning of Your annual Subscription, You will specify the expected monthly number of Active
                    Contributors (3 or more). You will be charged upfront for the Subscription fee, which will be calculated based on the
                    number of Active Contributors that You specified multiplied by the monthly fee per Active Contributor based on
                    Your Subscription Plan per each month of Your Subscription.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <menupath>Overuse</menupath> – Qodana will check the actual number of Active Contributors at the end of every calendar month. If the
                    actual number of Active Contributors exceeds the monthly number of Active Contributors that You specified, You will be
                    charged a Subscription fee for each Active Contributor exceeding the monthly number of prepaid Active Contributors. The
                    invoice for the overuse will be issued at the end of every calendar quarter and at the end of Your Subscription period
                    (unless the Subscription Period is renewed). If the number of actual Active Contributors during any month is lower than
                    the number of prepaid Active Contributors, We will not refund or otherwise credit the difference.
                </li>
            </list>
        </p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-cloud-license-storage" title="Where does Qodana store all license information?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
        <p>Qodana Cloud stores all information about your Ultimate and Ultimate Plus licenses. This explains why you
            need to create a Qodana Cloud account before running Qodana. Apart from this functionality, Qodana Cloud
            provides several <a href="cloud-use-cases.xml">helpful features</a>.
        </p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-license-difference" title="What is the difference between the Ultimate and Ultimate Plus licenses?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>Compared to the Ultimate license, the Ultimate Plus license provides the following additional features:</p>

        <list>
            <li><a href="license-audit.xml">License audit</a></li>
            <li><a href="taint-analysis.md">Taint analysis</a></li>
            <li><a href="vulnerability-checker.md"/></li>
        </list>

    </chapter>
    <chapter id="faq-licensing-community-restrictions" title="Are there any restrictions on using the Community license?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>No, you can use the Community version of Qodana in any open-source or proprietary projects.</p>

    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-licensing-license-cicd-integrations" title="Which licenses are integrated into CI/CD pipelines?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">

        <p>All %product% subscriptions support integration with the CI/CD solutions described in the <a href="ci.md"/> section.</p>

    </chapter>
    </chunk>
</chapter>

<chapter title="Troubleshooting" id="faq-troubleshooting">

    <chapter id="faq-zero-errors-report" title="Qodana reports zero errors, though I know it is not true." initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>Use the <code>qodana.recommended</code> inspection <a href="inspection-profiles.md" anchor="Default+profiles">profile</a>.</p>
    <p>If the problem persists, please create an issue in our tracker or contact us at <code>qodana-support@jetbrains.com</code> and
    attach logs from the <code>/data/results</code> directory that you can get access to by mounting your directory to the path.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-reduce-analysis-time" title="Is there a way to reduce analysis time?" initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>Yes, you can use <a href="docker-image-configuration.xml" anchor="docker-config-reference-cache-dependencies">caching</a>, and this
    is available by default in the <a href="github.md">Qodana Scan</a> GitHub action.  If this does not help, create an issue in
    our tracker or contact us at <code>qodana-support@jetbrains.com</code> and attach logs from the <code>/data/results</code>
    directory that you can access them mounting your directory to the path or if you are using GitHub actions, they are
    uploaded to the workflow artifacts.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-out-of-memory-error" title="Qodana fails with the Out of Memory error." initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>Try to set more memory in Docker Desktop preferences, as some projects and build tools inside them like Gradle could
    require more memory than the default 2GB.</p>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="faq-cannot-download-gradle" title="Qodana can't download Gradle because I use proxy." initial-collapse-state="collapsed">
    <p>Please run the <code>./gradlew</code> command in the root folder before starting %product%. The downloaded Gradle
    will be used by %product%.</p>
    <p>If your project was created on Windows, be sure to run <code>git update-index --chmod=+x gradlew</code> to make the
    file executable in your CI.</p>
    </chapter>

</chapter>

</topic>







