<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Baseline"
       id="qodana-baseline">

    <p><emphasis>Baseline</emphasis> is a snapshot of the codebase problems taken at a specific %product% run and
        contained in the <code style="inline">qodana.sarif.json</code> file.</p>

    <p>Using the baseline feature, you can compare your current code with its baseline state and see new, unchanged, and
        resolved problems.</p>

    <chapter title="How it works">

    <p>If you run %product% without a baseline, you will be able to see the problems detected at a current run.</p>

        <img src="baseline-no-baseline.png" dark-src="baseline-no-baseline_dark.png" width="705" alt="Running Qodana without baseline"/>

    <p>In this case, you can only see the number of problems and their description, without classification to new and
        existing problems. </p>

        <p>To improve the situation, you can add problems to the baseline, download the
            <code style="inline">qodana.sarif.json</code> file, and put it to your project directory as explained in the
            <a href="ui-overview.md" anchor="Baseline"/> section. Once done, this file becomes a basis for
            comparing with subsequent code states. You can run the baseline with the following CLI command:
        </p>

        <code style="block" lang="shell">
        docker run ... <![CDATA[jetbrains/qodana&minus;&lt;linter&gt; \
        &minus;&minus;baseline &lt;path-to-qodana.sarif.json&gt;]]>
        </code>

        <p>The baseline feature divides problems into these groups:</p>

        <list>
            <li><emphasis>Unchanged</emphasis> are the problems added to a baseline and remaining unchanged since then.</li>
            <li><emphasis>New</emphasis> are the problems that arise in addition to the baseline problems.</li>
            <li><emphasis>Absent</emphasis> are the baseline problems that were resolved since the baseline was created. </li>
        </list>

        <p>This image explains how everything works.</p>

        <img src="baseline-enabled.png" dark-src="baseline-enabled_dark.png" width="706" alt="Enabling the baseline"/>

    <list type="decimal">

        <li>The first %product% run detected two problems in the codebase.</li>

        <li>To create a baseline for your project, download the <code style="inline">qodana.sarif.json</code> file and
            save it to your project directory as shown in the <a href="ui-overview.md" anchor="Baseline"/> section.
            Starting from this moment, these two problems are identified by %product% as baseline problems.
        </li>

        <li>A subsequent %product% run detected three problems. Fortunately, this time %product%
            identifies one of them as new and marks it respectively. The other two are the baseline problems; they are
            already reflected in the baseline report and marked as unchanged.
        </li>

        <li><p>After one baseline problem is resolved, you decided to run %product% again. This time, the report will
            contain three problems. The new problem is the problem that was detected in the previous run and still
            remains new. There is also one unchanged problem that has not changed its status. Finally, the first
            baseline problem was resolved and now is marked as absent. </p>
            <p>To include absent problems into the report, you need to run %product% with the
                <code style="inline">--baseline-include-absent</code> option:</p>
            <code style="block" lang="shell">
            docker run ... <![CDATA[jetbrains/qodana&minus;&lt;linter&gt; \
            &minus;&minus;baseline &lt;path-to-qodana.sarif.json&gt; \
            &minus;&minus;baseline-include-absent]]>
            </code>
        </li>

    </list>

        <p>As you can see, new problems do not change the status across %product% runs. To transform them to unchanged,
            you need to update your baseline.</p>

        <img src="baseline-updating-baseline.png" dark-src="baseline-updating-baseline_dark.png" width="706" alt="Updating the baseline"/>

        <list type="decimal">
            <li>Download the <code style="inline">qodana.sarif.json</code> file again and save it to your project directory.</li>
            <li>Run %product% again to see the change in the problem status.</li>
        </list>
    </chapter>

</topic>
